Edward Ascan

Junior software developer with a background in SaaS sales. Passionate about web development processes, learning, and building challenging applications. Previously I worked as a Business Development Representative for a software company and have recently decided to pivot my career and learn how to build software myself. As a recent bootcamp graduate, I'm a quick learner, with strong communication, time management and collaborative skills and I excel in fast-paced environments.

Toronto, ON edward.ascan@me.com 416-669-7278

Github

https://github.com/eascan
<u>LinkedIn</u>

https://www.linkedin.com/in/edwardascan/

PROJECTS

Yalper

Developed a single page application (SPA) using ReactJS, NodeJS & ExpressJS, which also implements Google Oauth and Cloudinary APIs, to allow users to provide services & regular users to find service providers for their specific needs.

Front-end: ReactJS, Axios, HTML, SASS. **Back-end**: NodeJS, ExpressJS, PostgreSQL.

Interview Scheduler

Developed Interview Scheduler - a single page application (SPA) built using ReactJS. This application allows users to book and cancel interviews.

Front-end: ReactJS, HTML, SASS.

Back-end: NodeJS, ExpressJS, PostreSQL.

Testing: Jest, Storybook, Cypress.

<u>Mapple</u>

Developed Mapple - a multipage, fullstack application that saves and manages maps and map locations with tags for users. Maps are organized by interest and can be edited, organized and favourited.

Front-end: Javascript, Ajax, JQuery, HTML, SASS.

Back-end: NodeJS, ExpressJS, PostreSQL.

Tweeter

Tweeter is a simple, single-page application clone of Twitter. This application was built to practice introductory concepts of SPAs as well as to learn CSS.

Front-end: Javascript, Ajax, JQuery, HTML, CSS.

Back-end: NodeJS, ExpressJS.

TinyApp

TinyApp is a simple fullstack web application built with Node & Express that allows users to shorten long URLs.

Front-end: Javascript, Ajax, HTML, CSS.

Back-end: NodeJS, ExpressJS.

SKILLS

Languages: Javascript, Ruby, HTML, CSS.

Frameworks, libraries & environments: NodeJS, ReactJS, Ajax, Axios, Rails, JQuery, Bootstrap, SASS, Cypress, Jest, Mocha & Chai, Storybook.

Systems & Databases: SQL,

PostreSQL, Git.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sales Development Representative

Synapse, Toronto, 2019-2020.

Account Manager & Business Development

Flow Water, Toronto, 2018-2019.

Personal Trainer

GoodLife Fitness, North York, 2017-2018.

EDUCATION

Lighthouse Labs, Fullstack Web Development Diploma, Toronto, 2021

Queen's University, Bachelor of Science, Kingston, 2016 **St. Andrew's College**, Ontario Secondary School Diploma, Aurora, 2011

LANGUAGES

Bilingual: English & Russian.